BILLY MATHISON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

[] 615-986-8257

x wlmathison@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/billy-mathison

https://github.com/wlmathison

wlmathison.dev

ABOUT

I spent 16 years working in mental health, helping others solve their problems. Eventually I came to the realization that while I loved helping clients through their problems, ultimately I had no control over the final outcome. What I love most about being a software developer is that I have the ability to solve any problem. I still have the satisfaction of breaking something apart and trying to understand what the issue is. Now, I also get to solve that problem.

CAPSTONE PROJECTS

DRAM

I created Dram for my front-end capstone. Dram is a single page whiskey tasting application which allows users to participate in live whiskey tastings, view and share their reviews instantly, and provide searchable historical data. I built the application using React and used reactstrap for styling. I was able to use Dram at a live whiskey tasting in which 10 people used the application.

https://github.com/wlmathison/dram

GROUP PROJECTS

NUTSHELL

Nutshell was my third group project. It is a social platform that allows users to create, read, update, and delete tasks, news articles, and events. Users are able to communicate with one another through a chat room, including being able to create, read, update, and delete their most current message. During this project I was primarily responsible for building the navbar, friends sections, much of the login page, and more. The project was built using HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Grunt, and Browserify.

https://github.com/wlmathison/nutshell

AWARDS

TEAM MEMBER OF THE QUARTER, 2013Behavioral Health Group

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Development

TREVECCA NAZARENE UNIVERSITY

Master of Arts Counseling

MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science Psychology

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Nashville Software School (2019-present)

Intensive full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving.

- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- · Project management/tracking with Github Projects & Issue Tracking used during group projects
- · JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built single-page applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript libraries including React
- Task Automation with Grunt: Linting with ESLint
- Module bundling with Browserify
- Styled applications with CSS Frameworks Bootstrap and Reactstrap
- · Application design through white boarding dependencies and building ERD's
- Executed projects in an Agile environment, including ticketing, testing, daily stand-ups, pairprogramming, and team retrospectives
- Used C#/ASP.Net to develop a full-stack MVC web application with a RESTful API that enables users CRUD functionality for resources in a SQL database

OUTPATIENT THERAPIST Centerstone (2018–2019)

Not-for-profit health care organization providing mental health care, addiction treatment and community education.

- · Individual counseling
- · Group counseling for substance abuse
- · Conducted intake assessments
- · Participated in weekly team treatment meetings

PSYCHOLOGICAL ASSISTANT Kathryn Steele, Psy.D. (2016-2017)

Neuropsychological clinic using evidence based neurocognitive testing.

- Technologies used: Kareo, Q-interactive, Q-global, E-fax
- Administration and scoring of tests including: WAIS-IV, WMS-IV, DKEFS, MMPI-II RF, CVLT-II, MCMI-IV, RBANS Update
- · Wrote of Psychological and Neuropsychological reports
- Insurance coding and billing
- · Accounts Receivable

OFFICE MANAGER, THERAPIST, BILLING SPECIALIST Roy Asta (2008-2017)

Psychiatric clinic offering outpatient treatment of mental health disorders and substance abuse.

- Technologies used: MS Word, Excel, Therapist Helper
- (2010 2017) Billing Specialist
- · Medical billing/coding, patient billing, accounts receivable, account auditing, and credentialing
- (2010 2015) Therapist
- · Individual counseling
- · Intake of opiate dependent patients
- (2008 2010) Office Manager
- Managed daily activities of office including reception, medical billing/coding, patient billing, accounts
 receivable, authorizations, credentialing, maintenance of machinery, and medical transcription
- · Networking of all hardware, including wiring of office
- Training new employees

COUNSELOR (2011–2016)

Scales Nutrition (2012 - 2016)

Outpatient clinic specializing in assessment and treatment of eating disorders/substance abuse.

· Group counseling for eating disorders and substance abuse

Behavioral Health Group (2012 - 2014)

Outpatient clinic providing medication-assisted opioid addiction treatment services.

- · Substance abuse individual counseling
- Group counseling

Private Practice (2011 – 2015)

Private practice offering treatment of mental health disorders.

• Individual Counseling